<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; Parker</title>
    <description>Web Architect and Designer</description>
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Traversing Jquery</title>
        <description>&lt;header class=&quot;header--interior&quot;&gt;
 &lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Back to Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/apple-touch-icon.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;nav role=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a  href=&quot;/#work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;active&quot; href=&quot;/#thoughts&quot;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;


&lt;article class=&quot;page page--thoughts&quot;&gt;



  &lt;time datetime=&quot;2015-02-18T16:57:51Z&quot;&gt;
    15 January 2015
  &lt;/time&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading Time: &lt;span class=&quot;eta&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;h1 class=&quot;page-title&quot;&gt;Traversing JQuery&lt;/h1&gt;
  
   
  &lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are some really great ways to speed up your JQuery, (which is really what getting good at developing is all about) like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always descend from an #id&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chaining your methods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Traversing the DOM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And many more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&#39;d like to focus on traversing, since it&#39;s one of those magical features of JQuery that can be hard for beginners to comprehend.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s it all about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When first learning JQuery, the concept of traversing can be confusing. It&#39;s more typing, but it works faster. Why?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, check out this &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsperf.com/find-select-speed-test/3&quot;&gt;Speed Test&lt;/a&gt;
You&#39;ll see that the clear winner (by speed) is the traversal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the explanation in the simplest terms I can provide.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have a list of cheeses, wrapped in an unordered list with an id of &quot;kindofCheese&quot;, in a div with an id of &quot;cheese&quot;. With some basic knowledge of JQuery you may have learned that if you want to select the last cheese in that list, you would use the following code...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;$(document).ready(function() {
      $(&quot;#cheese li:last&quot;)
    });&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, that will grab the last list element, but refactoring your code using traversal can make this query run faster.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;$(document).ready(function() {
      $(&quot;#cheese&quot;).find(&quot;li&quot;).last()
    });&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That &lt;em&gt;.find&lt;/em&gt; method helps us traverse the DOM. It&#39;s similar to our first approach, as in it gets us the result we&#39;re looking for, but it&#39;s slightly faster because of a few reasons. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JQuery is a library built *on top* of javascript. Javascript runs natively in your browser, whereas JQuery has to process it&#39;s own javascript code before handing it to the browser. JQuery uses a selector library called [sizzle]. All you really need to understand here is that it&#39;s not native to the DOM, so it&#39;s slower.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here&#39;s where it gets tricky. When you use more than one element in a JQuery selector, it HAS to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://sizzlejs.com/&quot;&gt;Sizzle&lt;/a&gt; to process. On the flip-side, if you use single elements in your selector, JQuery utilizes native DOM methods _(like getElementsByClassName, and getElementsByTagName)_ so you can take advantage of the native DOM speed benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Short and Sweet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when you&#39;re building out your mega-giant-monolith application keep in mind that refactoring your javascript can save you a significant amount of speed by traversing the DOM natively. Likewise, you can just stop using JQuery, and go full-metal-jacket style into javascript so that you&#39;re only using native DOM methods. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this short article helps those who are beginning to learn JQuery to get a solid understanding of what things to look out for, so you can get started on the right foot and have an idea of where to start refactoring your code. 
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav--share&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/share&quot; class=&quot;popup&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&quot;paging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;prev&quot; href=&quot;/thoughts/2014/12/17/Ghost-buttons.html&quot; class=&quot;paging__link&quot; id=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Previous Post&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
      Ghost Buttons
    &lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;paging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;home&quot; href=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;paging__link&quot; id=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Go Home&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
      Game Over
    &lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/thoughts/2015/01/15/Traversing-jquery.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thoughts/2015/01/15/Traversing-jquery.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ghost Buttons</title>
        <description>&lt;header class=&quot;header--interior&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Back to Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/apple-touch-icon.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;nav role=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a  href=&quot;/#work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;active&quot; href=&quot;/#thoughts&quot;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;


&lt;article class=&quot;page page--thoughts&quot;&gt;


  
  &lt;time datetime=&quot;2015-02-18T16:57:51Z&quot;&gt;
    17 December 2014
  &lt;/time&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading Time: &lt;span class=&quot;eta&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;h1 class=&quot;page-title&quot;&gt;Ghost Buttons&lt;/h1&gt;
  
   
  &lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;With the rise of full-image backgrounds on websites, the ghost button style has become a go-to element design to create a unique call to action button that allows the background image to be seen through the button.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;h2&gt;Here are some &lt;a href=&quot;http://websiteswithghostbuttons.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll assume that you&#39;ve got a site built out with some links on it. Preferably a call-to-action link somewhere on your page that you&#39;d like to apply this style to. I would suggest using this button styling sparingly. No need to go all &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MghiBW3r65M&quot;&gt;Bob Ross&lt;/a&gt; on this technique. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll go over 3 styles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A basic style&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A hovered-color transition&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A size transition effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll start with assigning a class to your link element. Let&#39;s call this &quot;ghost-button&quot;. It should look something like this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ghost-button&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Clicky Click&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s look at the CSS of the basic ghost button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Basic ghost button&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  .ghost-button { 
  display: inline-block; 
  width: 200px; 
  padding: 8px;
  color: #fff;
  border: 1px solid #fff;
  text-align: center;
  outline: none;
  text-decoration: none;
  }
  .ghost-button:hover,
  .ghost-button:active {
  background-color: #fff;
  color: #000;
  }
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we&#39;re simply adding a background color and changing the color of the text to black so it will show on the (now) white background on hover and active states. Pretty simple, right? Alright, let&#39;s turn it up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;On hover-color transition ghost button&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;.ghost-button {
  display: inline-block;
  width: 200px;
  padding: 8px;
  color: #fff;
  background-color: transparent;
  border: 2px solid #fff;
  text-align: center;
  outline: none;
  text-decoration: none;
  -webkit-transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  -moz-transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  -ms-transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  -o-transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  }
  &lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  .ghost-button:hover,
  .ghost-button:active {
  background-color: #2a85c3;
  border-color: #3fbc9f;
  color: #fff;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This applies the transition property to gradually change the background color, border color, and text color to whatever you set the values to in the hover and active states. It&#39;s really smooth and it works on all modern browsers (including IE 10 and up).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last example is my favorite. it uses the same transition effect, but on the width of the element. It&#39;s a really neat way to animate a button and put emphasis on the CTA.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Size transition ghost button&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;.ghost-button {
  display: inline-block;
  width: 200px;
  line-height: 25px;
  padding: 8px;
  color: #fff;
  border: 2px solid #fff;
  text-align: center;
  outline: none;
  text-decoration: none;
  -webkit-transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  -moz-transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  -ms-transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  -o-transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  transition: all .3s ease-in-out;
  }&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;.ghost-button:hover,
  .ghost-button:active {
  width: 220px;
  }&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few things you could try out on this transition effect. Like the height. Since the transition-property is set to &quot;all&quot;, you can optionally set the hover and active states to include a height change (or anything else you want to transition). You can conditionally set this to just width by changing the transition-property to: 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;transition: width .3s ease-in-out;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add any properties to the hover and active states that you want to transition, but only if you&#39;ve set them in the parent element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we&#39;ve explored some different ghost button styles and took advantage of the transition property. You can really go wild with this, but in the essence of minimalism, don&#39;t. CTA&#39;s are there to affirm your decision, not to be a distraction.  Happy coding everyone! &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav--share&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/share&quot; class=&quot;popup&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&quot;paging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;prev&quot; href=&quot;/thoughts/2014/12/02/Getting-Started.html&quot; class=&quot;paging__link&quot; id=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Previous Post&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
      Getting Started
    &lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;paging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;next&quot; href=&quot;/thoughts/2015/01/15/Traversing-jquery.html&quot; class=&quot;paging__link&quot; id=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Next Post&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
      Traversing Jquery
    &lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/thoughts/2014/12/17/Ghost-buttons.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thoughts/2014/12/17/Ghost-buttons.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <description>&lt;header class=&quot;header--interior&quot;&gt;
 &lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Back to Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/apple-touch-icon.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;nav role=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a  href=&quot;/#work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;active&quot; href=&quot;/#thoughts&quot;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;


&lt;article class=&quot;page page--thoughts&quot;&gt;



  &lt;time datetime=&quot;2015-02-18T16:57:51Z&quot;&gt;
    2 December 2014
  &lt;/time&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading Time: &lt;span class=&quot;eta&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;h1 class=&quot;page-title&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h1&gt;
  
   
  &lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;&quot;So, who is this Parkerrr guy?&quot;, you may be asking. I&#39;m a marketer, a designer, and a developer. I&#39;m interested in products, and how people interact with them.&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A question that always enters my head when I look at a new product is, &quot;Why would someone use this?&quot;.  The answer is almost always related to the fact that it makes that person&#39;s life easier. What I like about marketing is the psychology around deciding to use a product. Design goes hand in hand with marketing, building visual cues, and defining the personality of a product, and development is the truly fun part to me. Building a product with the features customers need and want, and deciding which ones to start with. It&#39;s such a fun process to launch a product, and I  truly enjoy every part of the process.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I used to draw these super heroes with utility belts. Remember those Batman action figures that had specific kits? Like a Batman with an ice cannon. He had blue armor. It was a a unique approach to reimagining the default Batman style. It wasn&#39;t that the regular batman couldn&#39;t handle an ice cannon, it&#39;s just that a Batman designed specifically for it was so much cooler. My super hero designs were focused around really niche scenarios, like jungle warfare, or aerial recon. Each of them had specific tools and characteristics to get their job done. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is that some of the best products focus on solving a specific problem. They don&#39;t try to solve every single problem. The focus on the pain points of a niche, and build their products to ease those pain points. Take Github for example. Software development is a hell of a drug. When you&#39;re on a team, working on the same code, you want to make sure each developer is working with the most up-to-date code, and they have all the dependencies needed. Hosting your project on Github (and using revision control in general) relieves the pain point of developers sharing their code. Of course, Github is more than just a place to host code. They now handle Gantt charts, Photoshop file previews, documentation/wikis, and more. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My practice in marketing is backed by data. So Much Data. It&#39;s not just demographics anymore. It&#39;s about starting a conversation with your customers and following through on their response. Social Media certainly makes it easy to interact with current and potential customers, but that&#39;s just one touch point. My current focus is in email-based marketing. Communicating through email is still in it&#39;s prime. Yes, there&#39;s products like Slack that do a good job of limiting your interaction with your inbox, but much like your physical mailbox, you tend to check in more often than not. It&#39;s still a hub for communications for many people. Especially those who aren&#39;t big nerds. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;I&#39;m always interested in learning new techniques, in marketing, design, and development. I have so many ideas that while on paper, they&#39;re useless. So this site is all about me putting my ideas into action. I hope you enjoy!&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav--share&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/share&quot; class=&quot;popup&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&quot;paging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;prev&quot; href=&quot;/work/2014/03/12/RCS-Branding-Guidelines.html&quot; class=&quot;paging__link&quot; id=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Previous Post&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
      Rcs Branding Guidelines
    &lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;paging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;next&quot; href=&quot;/thoughts/2014/12/17/Ghost-buttons.html&quot; class=&quot;paging__link&quot; id=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Next Post&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
      Ghost Buttons
    &lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/thoughts/2014/12/02/Getting-Started.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thoughts/2014/12/02/Getting-Started.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rcs Branding Guidelines</title>
        <description>&lt;header class=&quot;header--interior&quot;&gt;
 &lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Back to Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/apple-touch-icon.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;nav role=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a  href=&quot;/#work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;active&quot; href=&quot;/#thoughts&quot;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;


&lt;article class=&quot;page page--work&quot;&gt;



  &lt;time datetime=&quot;2015-02-18T16:57:51Z&quot;&gt;
    12 March 2014
  &lt;/time&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading Time: &lt;span class=&quot;eta&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;h1 class=&quot;page-title&quot;&gt;RCS Branding Guidelines&lt;/h1&gt;
  
   
  &lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Creating a Brand is Hard Work. Just a few short months ago, I launched a re-branding for RCS.&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was only 1 month prior to that launch&lt;/em&gt; that I approached the CEO about where their brand stood in the eyes of our customers. We needed to refresh our customers on where we stood in our market, and what we are capable of. &lt;b&gt;That&#39;s where branding really comes in&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Let me start by introducing you to our new brand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rcs-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RCS New Logo&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Saying it Without Words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many great designers are able to communicate their message using only visual representation - *no actual words*. It&#39;s an incredibly versitile skill in today&#39;s world where images are used more to recapture the readers attention. My goal was to tell our customers just enough, while keeping our logo as simple and iconic as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;I&#39;ll rewind a bit to show you what I was working with&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rcs-old-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RCS Old Logo&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This logo was created for us a little over 5 years ago&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where to start? I decided to pick our colour palette first. Our original logo was in 2 colors, green and blue. In color theory, we&#39;re talking the color of money and trust. **Definitely want to keep those two colors, not only for those factors but also to stay familiar to our existing customer base**. I chose one primary color, a sort of light blue, and white for a clean and &quot;transparent&quot; aspect. I would end up using a green color for accent when developing our marketing materials.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rcs-guidelines-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Guidelines Document&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I wanted to make the RCS logo more iconic, and more recognizeable. So I went back to basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic shapes are by nature the most recognizeable. I&#39;m talking squares, circles, triangles. Like those blocks you played with as a kid, trying to fit them in the proper bucket. A square was the best fit for us. A strong foundational shape, with slightly rounded edges. It was a bit plain looking, so after some experimenting, I added a subtle gradient from left to right.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a bit more detail on the logo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rcs-logo-detail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Logo Detail&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close-up, you can see some of the more subtle effects. At smaller resolutions, the details are lost, but it keeps the same clean aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Refreshing our Web Presence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite thing about branding projects is seeing how all the pieces come together, *the website especially*. Our old site followed an overused layout, with little, to no uniqueness in it. **Full Disclosure** *I put that site together a little over 2 years ago.* In an effort to reclaim my Development creds, I went all out on the new website. Built on Wordpress, I implemented new features on the backend to track how our visitors were using it including:&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/em&gt; For tracking conversion points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inspectlet&lt;/em&gt; Awesome service that shows you exactly how your visitors are using your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;King Sumo Headlines&lt;/em&gt; A fantastic plugin that allows you to track which headline for your posts convert more visitors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cloudflare CDN&lt;/em&gt; Cloudflare provides great uptime, and response for serving your content efficiently.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disqus&lt;/em&gt; We wanted a way to provide a better commenting service. Disqus was the answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Authorship&lt;/em&gt; If you want to add an extra bump in your search engine results on Google, this is the quickest, and easiest way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bit.ly&lt;/em&gt; I created a custom Bit.ly shortURL generator with a unique domain name for tracking our links/pages and how they perform in our email newsletters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Schema Markup&lt;/em&gt; For events, and future items we&#39;ll be selling on our website.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a view of the current website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rcs-website.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New RCS Website&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following suit with our branding guidelines, this site is clean, yet colorful; informative, but casual. You can visit it at www.retailcontrolsystems.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final version was the result of many iterations, which our management team helped with, and tested with our customers. With **Inspectly** I was able to confirm interactions were working correctly, and as we iterate on the current site, I can continue my A/B testing to see which pages are succeeding in their goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav--share&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/share&quot; class=&quot;popup&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;div class=&quot;paging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;home&quot; href=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;paging__link&quot; id=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Go Home&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
      Game Over
    &lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;paging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;next&quot; href=&quot;/thoughts/2014/12/02/Getting-Started.html&quot; class=&quot;paging__link&quot; id=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Next Post&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
      Getting Started
    &lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt; </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/work/2014/03/12/RCS-Branding-Guidelines.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/work/2014/03/12/RCS-Branding-Guidelines.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>